<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[matt kaar]]></title>
  <link href="http://mattkaar.github.com/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://mattkaar.github.com/"/>
  <updated>2013-02-23T16:31:00-05:00</updated>
  <id>http://mattkaar.github.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Matt Kaar]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Raspberry Pi as a Baby Monitor]]></title>
    <link href="http://mattkaar.github.com/blog/2012/12/01/raspberry-pi-as-a-baby-monitor/"/>
    <updated>2012-12-01T10:41:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://mattkaar.github.com/blog/2012/12/01/raspberry-pi-as-a-baby-monitor</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>As we headed out of town for Thanksgiving, I was in search of my next tech project. On a whim I threw a <a href="http://www.raspberrypi.org">Raspberry Pi</a> and Yeti USB microphone in my bag, determined to create a networked, high-fidelity baby monitor.</p>

<p>It turned out to be easier than I thought.</p>

<p><img src="http://mattkaar.github.com/images/mk/raspberry_pi_monitor.jpg" width="315" height="315"></p>

<!-- more -->


<p>First, the Yeti worked without needing a powered USB hub… score. Then Raspbian picked it out without any issues.</p>

<pre><code>$ arecord -l
**** List of CAPTURE Hardware Devices ****
card 1: Microphone [Yeti Stereo Microphone], device 0: USB Audio [USB Audio]
  Subdevices: 1/1
  Subdevice #0: subdevice #0
</code></pre>

<p>Finally, I stumbled across <a href="http://mutsuda.com/2012/09/07/raspberry-pi-into-an-audio-spying-device/">this excellent blog post</a> from <a href="https://twitter.com/mutsuda">@mutsuda</a> that shows how to use <code>aplay</code> and <code>arecord</code> to send captured audio to a remote system for playback. With these instructions, you&#8217;ll need another Raspberry Pi or separate Linux system for the listening side.</p>

<div class='embed tweet'><blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-in-reply-to="271615902557036547"><p>@<a href="https://twitter.com/mattkaar">mattkaar</a> Fab. I&#8217;ve always thought monitors are absurdly expensive - wicked to exploit new parents&#8217; worries for $$$. Will you write it up?</p>&mdash; Raspberry Pi (@Raspberry_Pi) <a href="https://twitter.com/Raspberry_Pi/status/271617154087002112" data-datetime="2012-11-22T14:12:30+00:00">November 22, 2012</a></blockquote>
<script src="http://mattkaar.github.com//platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script></div>


<p>Here we go. First, make sure the levels are correct for both input and output (mine were muted by default).</p>

<pre><code>$ alsamixer
</code></pre>

<p>Then run this test capture on the Raspberry Pi.</p>

<pre><code>$ arecord -D plughw:1,0 -f cd -d 10 test.wav
</code></pre>

<p>And then this should play the test file out of headphone jack on the RPi.</p>

<pre><code>$ aplay test.wav
</code></pre>

<p>Finally, to send sound to a remote system, give this a shot.</p>

<pre><code>$ arecord -D plughw:1,0 -f dat | ssh -C user@remoteip aplay -f dat
</code></pre>

<p>You should hear remote audio out of the far end provided those mixer settings are correct too.</p>

<p>Enjoy your new Raspberry Pi baby monitor!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Craigslist searches delivered to your inbox]]></title>
    <link href="http://mattkaar.github.com/blog/2011/03/15/craigslist-searches-delivered-to-your-inbox/"/>
    <updated>2011-03-15T10:54:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://mattkaar.github.com/blog/2011/03/15/craigslist-searches-delivered-to-your-inbox</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Nat and I are on the hunt for a leather ottoman. Some guy on Craigslist sold his after promising it to us, and its been hard to find another since.</p>

<p><img src="http://mattkaar.github.com/images/mk/craigslist_ottoman.png" width="448" height="355"></p>

<p>With a search only returning six hits, what we really needed was Craigslist to notify us when new ottomans get posted. Craigslist won&#8217;t do this on its own, but with the help of <a href="http://feedmyinbox.com/">FeedMyInbox</a>, searching for our new ottoman became a whole lot easier.</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>There are just two steps to this trick:</p>

<ol>
<li><p>After searching for an item on Craigslist, <strong>copy the URL from the results page</strong>.</p>

<p> <img src="http://mattkaar.github.com/images/mk/craigslist_copy.png"></p></li>
<li><p>Head over to <a href="http://feedmyinbox.com/">FeedMyInbox</a> and paste the URL where it says <strong>Website or Feed URL</strong>. Then <strong>add your email address</strong> and click <strong>Submit</strong>.</p>

<p> <img src="http://mattkaar.github.com/images/mk/feedmyinbox.png" width="544" height="344"></p></li>
</ol>


<p>You&#8217;ll receive a confirmation email with a CONFIRM link – don&#8217;t forget to click it. And that&#8217;s it! Sit back and watch new Craigslist results come straight to your inbox.</p>

<p><strong>UPDATE (11/23/12):</strong> FeedMyInbox just announced they&#8217;re shutting down their service. They recommend <a href="http://blogtrottr.com/">Blogtrottr</a> as a substitute, but I haven&#8217;t tried it out yet.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Addendum: Amazon EC2 VPN with Windows]]></title>
    <link href="http://mattkaar.github.com/blog/2010/12/08/addendum-amazon-ec2-vpn-with-windows/"/>
    <updated>2010-12-08T19:43:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://mattkaar.github.com/blog/2010/12/08/addendum-amazon-ec2-vpn-with-windows</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://twitter.com/mascasa">@Mascasa</a> recently wrote some excellent instructions on setting up OpenVPN using Amazon Web Services and getting connected with a Mac client:</p>

<p><a href="http://www.stratumsecurity.com/blog/2010/12/03/shearing-firesheep-with-the-cloud/">www.stratumsecurity.com/blog/2010/12/03/shearing-firesheep-with-the-cloud/</a></p>

<p>It turns out connecting with Windows is easy too. Here&#8217;s how I did it…</p>

<!-- more -->


<ol>
<li>Download and install the <strong>OpenVPN GUI for Windows</strong> from <a href="http://openvpn.se/download.html">here</a> (the full Installation Package). Accept all the defaults when installing.</li>
<li>Download the same keys and certificates used in the Mac setup (<strong>ca.crt</strong>, <strong>ta.key</strong>,<strong><em>yourname</em>.crt</strong> and <strong><em>yourname</em>.key</strong>) to your Windows machine. You might need a client like <a href="http://winscp.net/eng/download.php">WinSCP</a> to pull them off the EC2 server.</li>
<li>Download the client template <a href="http://www.stratumsecurity.com/sites/default/files/ec2.conf">here</a> and rename it to <strong>EC2_VPN.ovpn</strong>. Open it in WordPad and change the hostname and cert/key filenames (lines 42 and 89-90).</li>
<li>Copy all of the files (<em>.key, </em>.crt and *.ovpn) to the OpenVPN configuration directory (usually <strong>\Program Files\OpenVPN\config</strong>).</li>
<li>Right-click on the OpenVPN icon in the system tray and click <strong>Connect</strong>.</li>
</ol>


<p><img src="http://mattkaar.github.com/images/mk/openvpn_connect.png"></p>

<p>That&#8217;s it. Visit <a href="http://ipchicken.com/">IPChicken</a> and check that your Amazon IP appears. And leave a comment if you run into problems.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Hooked on Instapaper]]></title>
    <link href="http://mattkaar.github.com/blog/2010/08/29/hooked-on-instapaper/"/>
    <updated>2010-08-29T00:49:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://mattkaar.github.com/blog/2010/08/29/hooked-on-instapaper</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>If there&#8217;s one browsing tool I like more than <a href="http://mattkaar.github.com/blog/2010/07/27/single-minded-browsing-using-safari-reader">Safari Reader</a>/<a href="http://mattkaar.github.com/blog/2010/08/09/how-to-install-ireader-for-firefox">iReader</a>, it&#8217;s <a href="http://instapaper.com">Instapaper</a>. Reading articles during the day drives me to distraction, and Instapaper allows me to save off interesting stuff for later consumption.</p>

<p>To get started, head over to <a href="http://instapaper.com">instapaper.com</a> and register for an account. I recommend setting a password too, but it&#8217;s not required. Then click and drag the <strong>Read Later</strong> button to the bookmarks bar in your browser (that&#8217;s Chrome for Mac below.)</p>

<!-- more -->


<p><img src="http://mattkaar.github.com/images/mk/instapaper.png" width="462" height="442"></p>

<p>And that&#8217;s it! When you stumble across a long web article, just click that Read Later bookmark. Once you have time to read, open up Instapaper and click the Text button next to each story — they&#8217;ll show up without any annoying ads.</p>

<p>Finally, there&#8217;s an iPad/iPhone app for when you&#8217;re away from your computer. And Kindle owners can download all of their articles using the Kindle link on the right-hand side of the main site. So many options!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[How to install iReader for Firefox]]></title>
    <link href="http://mattkaar.github.com/blog/2010/08/09/how-to-install-ireader-for-firefox/"/>
    <updated>2010-08-09T20:28:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://mattkaar.github.com/blog/2010/08/09/how-to-install-ireader-for-firefox</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="http://mattkaar.github.com/images/mk/ireader_icon.png" width="50" height="50"></p>

<p>Mom, the last time I posted about Safari Reader you asked me if it&#8217;s something you could use.</p>

<p>Since you&#8217;re a Firefox user, you can&#8217;t use that exact feature, but there&#8217;s an add-on called iReader that works much the same way. By the way, Clark Howard uses Google Chrome now (I know you&#8217;re a fan.)</p>

<p>But no worries, Firefox is still a fine browser. And here&#8217;s my best attempt to walk you through installing something on your computer without logging in and doing it for you. :)</p>

<p>Here we go…</p>

<!-- more -->


<ol>
<li><p>Click here → <a href="https://addons.mozilla.org/en-US/firefox/addon/195787/">iReader :: Add-ons for Firefox</a>.  That will load a separate tab with this in it:</p>

<p> <img src="http://mattkaar.github.com/images/mk/ireader_1.png"></p></li>
<li><p>Click <strong>Add to Firefox</strong>.</p>

<p> <img src="http://mattkaar.github.com/images/mk/ireader_2.png"></p></li>
<li><p>A warning screen will appear.  You&#8217;ll have to trust me on this one.  Click <strong>Add to Firefox</strong> again.</p>

<p> <img src="http://mattkaar.github.com/images/mk/ireader_3.png"></p></li>
<li><p>Firefox is really paranoid with warning you about software.  Read the text and click <strong>Install Now</strong>.</p>

<p> <img src="http://mattkaar.github.com/images/mk/ireader_4.png"></p></li>
<li><p>In order to enable the add-on, you&#8217;ve got to restart Firefox.  Luckily, there&#8217;s a convenient <strong>Restart Firefox</strong> button in the next window that appears.  Click that button.</p>

<p> <img src="http://mattkaar.github.com/images/mk/ireader_5.png"></p></li>
<li><p>Finally surf to any long web article like this one.  You should see <strong>a little &#8216;R&#8217; icon</strong> in the address bar.  Go ahead and click it.</p>

<p> <img src="http://mattkaar.github.com/images/mk/ireader_6.png"></p></li>
<li><p>Now enjoy easier reading and no ads.</p></li>
</ol>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Single-minded browsing using Safari Reader]]></title>
    <link href="http://mattkaar.github.com/blog/2010/07/27/single-minded-browsing-using-safari-reader/"/>
    <updated>2010-07-27T00:41:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://mattkaar.github.com/blog/2010/07/27/single-minded-browsing-using-safari-reader</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I&#8217;ll admit it — I forward my fair share of web articles to family and friends. Unfortunately, with small font sizes and distracting ads, my eyes tire out quickly after page 3 of most long articles.</p>

<p>Enter the <a href="http://www.apple.com/safari/whats-new.html#reader">new Reader button in Safari 5</a>.</p>

<p><img src="http://mattkaar.github.com/images/mk/reader_button.png" width="283" height="53"></p>

<p>Reader displays an article&#8217;s text in a readable font size and greys out the rest of the clutter.  It&#8217;ll also consolidate multi-page articles to a single page.</p>

<p>For those not on Safari, the <a href="https://addons.mozilla.org/en-US/firefox/addon/195787/">iReader extension for Firefox</a> and <a href="https://chrome.google.com/extensions/detail/ppelffpjgkifjfgnbaaldcehkpajlmbc">Chrome</a> gives you the same clutter-free reading goodness.</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>Check out how Reader handles <a href="http://www.nytimes.com/2010/07/27/health/27brod.html">this New York Times article on Vitamin D deficiency</a>.</p>

<p><img src="http://mattkaar.github.com/images/mk/nytimes_article.png" width="552" height="406"></p>

<p><img src="http://mattkaar.github.com/images/mk/safari_reader.png" width="512" height="339"></p>

<p>Now when will they give us the same thing on the iPad??</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Kindle, how low will you go?]]></title>
    <link href="http://mattkaar.github.com/blog/2010/07/01/kindle-how-low-will-you-go/"/>
    <updated>2010-07-01T08:17:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://mattkaar.github.com/blog/2010/07/01/kindle-how-low-will-you-go</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="http://mattkaar.github.com/images/mk/woot_kindle.png" width="359" height="168"></p>

<p>Oh Amazon, how you tempt me…</p>

<p>Yesterday, Woot announced they&#8217;re getting acquired by Amazon. Now they have the latest Kindle for $150.</p>

<p>After devouring some great books on the Kindle recently, I really wanted to share them with Nat.  Buying physical copies could start to add up, so while writing this post, I broke down and bought a second Kindle.  Geek toys, you will be my downfall.</p>

<p><strong>UPDATE (9:24 AM ET):</strong> Looks like it sold out.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[iPhone 4: To upgrade or not, that's the question]]></title>
    <link href="http://mattkaar.github.com/blog/2010/06/15/iphone-4-to-upgrade-or-not/"/>
    <updated>2010-06-15T00:35:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://mattkaar.github.com/blog/2010/06/15/iphone-4-to-upgrade-or-not</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="http://mattkaar.github.com/images/mk/iphone4.jpg" width="360" height="270"></p>

<p>Being between jobs this week has me with free time, and my iPhone 3GS is burning a hole in my pocket right now.</p>

<p>I&#8217;d love to upgrade, but I&#8217;m not too keen on signing another contract with AT&amp;T–service in the DC area isn&#8217;t stellar.  And Nat&#8217;s on Verizon (she gets free calls to her parents), and she&#8217;s not leaving anytime soon. My money&#8217;s on <a href="http://www.eweek.com/c/a/Mobile-and-Wireless/Verizon-Executive-Calls-CDMA-iPhone-Inevitable-671780/">Verizon getting the iPhone sometime this year</a>, but I&#8217;ll still be under contract for another six months at that point.</p>

<p>What&#8217;s weird is that AT&amp;T&#8217;s offering to upgrade for only $18, even though I purchased my current phone less than a year ago. Used 3GS&#8217;s are going for $350 on eBay, so I could upgrade for nothing and only have the contract to worry about. This is the dilemma, and not having a job to occupy my time isn&#8217;t helping…</p>

<p>Thoughts?</p>

<p><strong>UPDATE:</strong> Maybe I&#8217;ll wait a little while, <a href="http://gizmodo.com/5563909/">things aren&#8217;t exactly smooth sailing for AT&amp;T today</a>.</p>

<p><strong>UPDATE 2:</strong> Looks like <a href="http://techcrunch.com/2010/06/15/iphone-4-sold-out/">I waited too long…</a></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Switching gears after four great years]]></title>
    <link href="http://mattkaar.github.com/blog/2010/05/22/switching-gears-after-four-great-years/"/>
    <updated>2010-05-22T07:32:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://mattkaar.github.com/blog/2010/05/22/switching-gears-after-four-great-years</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="http://mattkaar.github.com/images/mk/mitre_to_cert.png" width="500" height="165"></p>

<p>I&#8217;m leaving my job at <a href="http://www.mitre.org">MITRE</a> for a new one at <a href="http://www.cert.org">CERT</a>.</p>

<p>The decision wasn&#8217;t an easy one. Four years ago, MITRE hired me straight out of <a href="http://www.ini.cmu.edu">grad school</a> to help engineer cross domain solutions for the Government. Problem was, I&#8217;d never heard of a cross domain solution. Turns out, they&#8217;re computers that connect different classified networks to help with information sharing.</p>

<p>I learned a ton about these systems - what they do, and what they don&#8217;t do. Turns out, they have to be pretty secure - we are talking about national security after all. And along the way, I led a big deployment that&#8217;ll help warfighters share information a lot easier.</p>

<p>Fast forward four years, and I&#8217;m ready for my next adventure. CERT needed a developer for their new <a href="http://www.cert.org/archive/pdf/trifold.pdf">XNET exercise network</a> (pdf). I saw a new challenge and the opportunity to get back to development work. Oh, and Nat and I get to stay in the DC area (score!)</p>

<p>Just wanted to say thanks to everyone who made the past four years so memorable. If the next four are as exciting, I&#8217;ll be one lucky guy.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
